"Interesting question showed up
this morning. What does it feel
like to imagine the person you
truly want to become?"
"It feels like I'm taking whatever
I imagine and putting it out
somewhere into the future, like
someday.
That day that never comes. And to
feel what it is to imagine
something I truly want to become is
a bit of a conundrum,
at least the way I'm breaking it
down when I'm thinking about this
slowly.
Because I can just knee-jerk
reaction this question, you know,
and say, "What does it
feel like to imagine the person you
truly want to become?" "Oh, I feel
a bit excited, a bit fearful, like
fear, excitement, and blah, blah,
blah."
You know, it's all very, I don't
know, it's of the moment. It's not
really reflection in a way.
And for some reason, this question
just made me, I don't know if it's
tap the brakes or
just totally come to a stop and go,
"Okay, we're going to read this one
word at a time.
What does it feel like?" So we're
asking, "What's this feeling?" And
feeling is a body thing, not a
thinking thing.
So right there, that kind of throws
me off. Because I have for 90,
greater than 98% of the 56 years
I've lived has been spent in
my head, very little time spent in
my heart or in my body, more
somatic in nature.
So when the question leads with,
"What does it feel like?" My knee-
jerk is to think of a feeling.
When I'm slowing down, I'm suddenly
searching my body for a feeling. So
what does it feel like to imagine,
"Okay, so now you're asking me to
use my head.
So what does it feel like in my
body?" Not what does it feel like
when I think about this, what
feeling comes to inside my head
when I imagine the person I truly
want to become. So the question is
basically saying you are not that
person right now when you stop and
think about it. Because if you're
imagining the person you truly want
to become, right now you are not
that person, at least the way this
question reads. So in some sense,
what this question is doing is
asking you to imagine what it feels
like
to be something you're not right
now in this moment. What does it
feel like to imagine the person you
truly want to become?
Because in this moment, you are not
that person. I forgot to finish the
question.
So yeah, it's kind of a weird
breakdown of this, but when I go
through it the way that
I'm breaking it down and I'm going
to do it backwards, right? So
instead of what does it feel, what
does it feel like, I'm going to
start with the
person you truly want to become. I
would submit that I am not
becoming.
I submit that I am in a continual
state of being, of existing,
because I can only be
in this moment. Any other place is
time travel. Think of the future,
imagine the future, you are time
traveling to the future.
Your brain isn't here in this
moment, right now, your brain is in
the future, thinking
about something that hasn't
happened yet, which in most cases
is people freaking out
and having fear about something,
imagining something that hasn't
even happened yet.
The old Burt would say, you know
what, we need to think about all
the 75 million possible
bad things that can happen just so
we're ready. That's old Burt. You
know, I'm just being in the moment
and whatever shows up, shows up.
And I go forward in that moment
with what I know, where I am, and
what resources I have
at my disposal and what level of
agency I have over myself. So what
does it feel like to imagine the
person you truly want to become?
I submit that I am that person and
I am always in the becoming because
time is moving forward
and now moves forward linearly
through time. So if I am a sentient
being who is conscious, I am being
brought through time in a line
and I cannot escape that until I
cease to exist in this form as
Burt, then I don't
know what happens. You can go
online and read all kinds of shit
about people who have had the near
death experiences
and there's a lot of similarity
among the stories just like the,
you know, alien abductee
people. Yeah. It's just a lot of
weird shit. And what was cool was
before the internet, you didn't
know about most of this shit.
It was basically out of sight, out
of mind, or better yet, let's go
Donnie Rumsfeld and
say it was things I didn't know
that I didn't know. It's just like
not even in your head or in your
imagination.
So when I imagine who I am being in
this moment in preparation for the
next moment, I am now
in this moment feeling okay. I'm
not feeling poor or fair or
moderate. I'm feeling okay, which
metaphorically means my head is
above the water, but my arms and
legs are underneath the water
treading calmly, right? But I'm
working to keep my head above the
water.
So I'm in that process of just,
yeah, basically just treading water
until I get a leg up to
get out of the water and start
plugging back into the world. So in
my breakdown of this question, what
would be powerful is if in this
continual
moment of being, I were able to
take my faculties, my energy, my
frequency, and pour it into
projects that help people in some
way, connect to others, connect to
themselves, connect
to their family, connect to the
world, it gets them out of their
head, gets them out
of their bubble, gets them out from
under the bridge, gets them out of
their basement,
gets them out of the attic,
actually gets them out and
interacting with another human
being. I was ready to call this
whole thing quits more than once in
the past three years.
And I stuck it out. And always
being in this moment, there are
times I have no idea where I will
be on this
timeline, you know, a day, 10 days,
a year from now, because I can only
be in this moment.
But the things I do in this moment
determine where I show up on that
timeline.
The timeline's gonna happen, I'm
moving through it, you're moving
through it, we're all moving
through it. But where you end up
and how you end up there is all
based on the now.
What are you doing right now with
your resources, your agency, your
energy, your frequency,
and your abilities, I guess that's
the more important question to be
asking is what does
it feel like to think about all
those things in this moment? Does
it cause dread?
Does it make you feel possibility,
opportunity? Does it feel
overwhelmed?
Does it make you shake inside? Does
it make you want to run and hide? I
guess that's me flipping the
question back on itself after doing
all this jabbering.
I think I'll end it there for now.
I got a lot of shit to do, I need
to make some money.
Okay, peace out, be well.